Okay, so we've probably all um done some
CSS before or hopefully you've done a
little bit had a little bit of exposure
to CSS. This is not a CSS course. I'm
just going to show you a little bit
about CSS selectors. Um so I have here
this body tag. What I'm saying is go
find the body tag and apply that
background color to it. So if we look at
our website, boom, there our website has
that background color.
And we can actually target specific
elements on our page. So we could say
set every H1 to have a color of um aqua.
Um and now we can see that both H1 tags
are now set to aqua.
You can actually get some more
fine-tuned control over this. So let's
say I want to target this H1 tag which
is inside of this div. If I want to do
that, I could say, "Go find a div, and
immediately inside that div, if there's
an H1 tag, then I want you to apply a
style to it." And I'll say, "Set the
color equal to um
that color, that white." Um, and if we
do that, we will see that we have a
white H1 tag. Even though we said set H
all set all H1 tags to be color aqua, we
were able to specifically find this H1
tag because it's inside of a div and we
were able to target it. And so just by
typing out just that short line of text,
we were able to target that specific H1
tag.
And um this is super super powerful um
because it allows you to type very
little code and target a very specific
element on the page. And you can
actually take advantage of this in
JavaScript.